Why are you taking it off ? Come sit .
Bulbbul !
Bulbbul ?
Where is this girl ?
Caught you !
On the trees again .
Who is this , Auntie ?
Bit of a scruffy urchin ,
but we will take of her .
Hey !
He 's right .
Now I have to get you ready all over again .
Auntie , why do I have to wear toe rings ?
Because there 's a nerve here .
If it is not pressed , girls tend to fly away .
Like a bird ?
No . It is to control you .
Auntie
what 's " control " ?
Auntie !
Dad ! Auntie !
What are you doing , you lunatic ?
She must have gotten frightened .
Auntie .
Do you want to listen to a story ?
Is it a scary story ?
Yes .
Sure .
A long , long time ago
there was a Demon-Woman .
She lived on trees in the deep , dark woods .
She had feet that were twisted all the way around .
That blood-thirsty demon waited ,
and waited for the day
when the princess would come ,
so that she could gobble her up .
Doll .
Mahendra !
I forbade you to come here , didn 't I ?
Doll .
Binodini .
Can 't you keep your husband in check ?
Forgive me , Milord .
Mahendra
my brother .
He 's like a kid .
Where is he ?
Who ?
My husband .
That 's me .
No . He was small like me .
He was with me in the palanquin .
He told me a story .
His name was ...
Satya .
When you grow up , you 'll know the difference
between a husband and a brother-in-law .
Slow down !
Sorry , Sir Satya .
This place is not safe .
There is danger here .
She lives here .
Who ?
The Demon-Woman .
You woke up , Sire ?
Go to sleep . I will wake you up once we reach the manor .
Is sister-in-law asleep ?
Yes , Sire .
- May I serve you dinner ? - No . It 's fine .
Please don 't be upset , Milady .
Too late for that .
And what will your poor first wife do ?
They 'll live together like sisters .
Get out .
If she suffers in any way , you 'll have to answer to me .
Are you playing at lord of the manor , sister-in-law ?
One , two ...
Three , four ...
Five , six ...
Seven , eight ...
Nine , ten ...
Eleven , 12 ...
Then what happened ?
Then the Demon-Woman blew out all the candles in the princess 's room .
Fool !
Then ?
She tiptoed to the princess 's bed , and ...
To what do we owe the pleasure of your visit ?
Oh , I see . Come to check on your inheritance , have you ?
Sister-in-law ...
Haven 't heard from you for five years .
It can 't be that you suddenly missed me .
I wrote to His Lordship ,
and always asked after you .
He didn 't respond .
I wanted to come three years ago
when Mahendra ... was killed .
They say that
the Demon-Woman killed him .
And you believe this nonsense ?
Not at all .
Binodini says so .
So much has changed in these past five years .
Even His Lordship left home .
What went wrong ?
Would you like to meet Binodini ?
Binodini .
Little brother .
The goddess has not done right by me .
Really ?
How can you say the rosary and curse god in the same breath ?
A litany of prayers feels like a lament .
Spent my whole life praying ,
and see
what I got in return .
I was immersed in prayers when the Demon-Woman killed Mahendra .
Now , even if someone dies of a fever or falls off a tree ,
people blame it on the Demon-Woman .
Really ?
Did Mahendra have a fever ?
He was lying there drowned in his own blood .
You witnessed it .
Sounds like an animal attack .
Do you remember Brother Indranil used to tell us of a man-eating tiger ?
There were bloody twisted footprints ... on the floor .
It was the Demon-Woman .
The same nonsense again .
There 's been no Demon-Woman until now .
Where did she suddenly appear from ?
From the trees .
What ...
Then ? Go on .
She tiptoed to the princess 's bed , and ...
What are you two doing in the dark ?
Why do you spoil everything ?
I 'm so sorry , Milady .
I just came to tell you that your husband needs you .
Why ?
I have no idea .
He should ask for me .
I 'm the one who takes care of him .
I don 't know why he still wants his Bulbbul .
How does one tell him
that his Bulbbul only wants Satya ?
She sleeps during the day .
Hunts at night .
All right .
So even I will hunt at night .
Binodini will only be satisfied
when you 've stuffed and mounted the head of the Demon-Woman on the wall .
Tiger , deer ...
Demon-Woman !
Where did the sweet little lady I knew disappear ?
What did you do with her ?
I gobbled her up .
Where is Her Ladyship ?
She 's downstairs in the veranda .
You 're obsessed with my feet .
How observant of you .
Hey , have you met Dr. Sudip ?
Doctor ?
Is everything okay ?
Yes .
He just came to visit .
I will leave now . I have got to go check on her .
When will that master mend his ways ?
Which master ?
Master Dinkar .
He 's a fine man .
His wife 's broken bones tell another story .
She is also of no help . She keeps saying .
" I fell off the stairs . "
So maybe it 's true .
There is only one house in this place that has stairs .
Milady .
How many times have I told you not to call me " Milady " ?
Whatever you say ... Milady .
Do you want to go on a hunt with Sir Satya ?
I save lives . I don 't know how to take them .
Sire .
Why do you look so annoyed ?
You 're not even veiled .
Go .
Aren 't you getting late for your hunt ?
- Master Dinkar . - Yes , Sir Satya .
- Are these all the men you could gather ? - Everyone is afraid of the Demon-Woman ...
Enough of this nonsense . Let 's go .
Sir Satya !
Sire , at least now you know that it is the Demon-Woman .
A murderer .
It 's a human being .
A man .
Inform the police officer that someone killed Master Dinkar .
Yes , Sire .
I live close by .
We can keep the body there for the night .
You stay so close to the forest .
Did you see ,
or hear anything ?
No .
Nothing .
Neither an animal ,
nor a human .
Nothing .
How was the hunt ?
Master Dinkar was killed .
And it wasn 't an animal .
It 's the work of a man .
Why ?
Why not a woman ?
What woman is capable of such a brutal murder ?
Milady .
Feels like ... nothing has changed .
The two of you
chatting away .
To what do we owe this pleasure ?
Satya did not tell you ?
He asked me to come .
He said you are all alone here
day and night .
Anyone can walk right in and take advantage of you .
- That 's why I ... - No .
I just thought it is Mahendra 's death anniversary .
- Right . - I thought we could all be together .
And you would want to hold a prayer meet for him .
Right ?
The police officer is here , Milady .
Tell him I 'm coming .
Now I 'm here , sister-in-law , you can relax .
It behooves us to do what we are meant to .
You are the lady of the house , not the lord .
What I mean is
how long will you do everything ?
You look exhausted .
Maybe because of the color , or maybe gray does not suit you .
Everyone is not as fortunate as you
to look nice even in dull , plain clothes .
♪ Oh , my . ♪
♪ You shameless hussy . ♪
♪ Why do you walk down the garden path . ♪
♪ When you know ♪ ♪ It leads to that bastard ? ♪
Milady .
Come .
Sit . Come .
Let me oil your hair .
Later ?
The jewelers have sent new things .
Have a look .
Aren 't they exquisite ?
At least choose a trinket or two .
As it is , you hardly got anything from home .
You look like a drab little thing decked up in all your dowry .
What if people say
I look more like the lady of the house than you do ?
I don 't care .
Yes . You care nothing for what people say or think .
At least get new toe rings .
Yours seem to have loosened a bit .
I 'll take it later .
♪ Oh , my . ♪
♪ You shameless hussy . ♪
♪ Throwing caution to the winds . ♪
♪ Oh , why ? Oh , why ? ♪ ♪ Oh , why do you cross the threshold ? ♪
♪ I beg of you . ♪
- Rest in peace ! - Rest in peace !
Subhashish , what is the point of being a police officer ?
There have been so many murders , but you don 't even have any suspects .
Suspicions do not count .
Our British law asks for proof .
Let 's go , Master .
A murderer .
It 's a human being .
A man .
You stay so close to the forest .
Did you see anything ... or hear anything ?
Shall I make paan ?
Sister-in-law , since when has the doctor been here ?
He was
here before your brother left home .
Does he
visit here a lot ?
It 's not like I live here .
How would I know ?
When you were here , did he visit then ?
We were just talking about you .
I should leave .
I have some work with the police officer . I will see you at dinner .
He was questioning me about Sudip .
Dr. Sudip is
a fine man .
Maybe it was just a casual query .
And you were adding your two bits .
Me ?
I didn 't .
Milady , you know me .
I never mean any harm or say anything bad about anyone .
Shall I make paan ?
Yes . Go right ahead .
Bulbbul .
No .
- Play ... - Please don 't .
Mahendra .
Is he sulking ?
Satya .
Brother .
Come here !
Happy ?
I 've asked the groundsman to pluck some mangoes .
Will you make some relish for me ,
or are you going to eat them all yourself ?
Paan ?
So
I got you some perfume .
So have you thought about the proposal ?
Proposal ?
The marriage proposal for Satya .
I had told you .
Madam , what do you think ?
" Madam " ?
No .
I think I put too much catechu in the paan .
A slip of the tongue .
I
I meant ... " Milady . "
So tell us , Milady .
Should we get Satya married ?
Why do you need to ask her ?
Hey .
She has the first claim to Satya .
Shouldn 't we check with her before we get someone else for him ?
Shouldn 't we ask Satya ?
What ?
About the proposal ... that Binodini has got for him .
You 're not happy about it .
When I write my bit as a straightforward story ,
you turn it into a spooky one .
Now , where did this girl 's ghost come from ?
You wrote this bit . Now explain it to me .
Sister-in-law
wasn 't your childhood home blue in color ?
Why don 't we color this place blue ?
It 's looking a little shabby ,
and that way , you won 't miss your childhood home .
Why do we need to paint it ?
- It 's fine . - Hey .
We both sit and write here .
Shouldn 't it look pretty ?
Where will you get the time to write after you are married ?
Married ?
Binodini has got a proposal for you .
I 'm not getting married .
Everyone gets married .
Priests don 't ,
minstrels don 't ,
neither do owls .
And if you all force me to ,
I will become like a gypsy and roam around singing songs .
♪ Oh , my . ♪
♪ You shameless hussy . ♪
It 's not his fault .
It 's his age .
He spends all his time with her .
This was bound to happen .
Why don 't you ever wear shoes ?
It 's exhausting how you never learn .
I am making arrangements for you to go to London .
Really ?
I have told Binodini .
You can always get married later .
- First , complete your education . - London ?
Don 't you remember ?
I mentioned that Satya will go to London to study law .
But don 't just study .
Travel , have fun .
And then write me letters telling me everything .
I 'll write every single week .
But now ?
- He has to leave now ? - Not now .
After the festival .
We will need to get warm clothes stitched for you .
I 've heard it gets cold there .
Snows as well .
But , Milord , the festival is only three months away .
How will we arrange everything ?
It 's not like you have to do anything .
Why don 't you come along ?
Not now . Maybe later .
Just three months .
I have written my bit .
Now you have to write the rest .
How will we ever complete this story ?
There is still time .
What about that house by the pond ?
You were going to have it painted .
I will before I leave .
Then you can sit there and write .
I 'm scared of being there alone .
I 'm scared of being here alone .
Who will talk to me now ? Whom will I.
I will write every day .
I will come back soon .
What if you don 't ? Then ?
At least light the lamp .
What is that ?
Nothing .
Why do you look so guilty , Bulbbul ?
No .
That is ... It 's just
something personal .
The only thing personal in a wife 's life is her husband .
I 'm headed to Calcutta
along with Satya .
Why ?
Why are you taking Satya ?
We have to get ... his travel documents prepared .
One , two ...
Three , four ...
Five , six ...
Seven , eight ...
Nine , ten ...
Eleven , 12 ...
Thirteen , 14 ...
Ready or not , Here I come !
Oh , you 're back , Milord ?
Satya ?
I 've sent him to London .
SATYAJEET THAKUR MRS. BULBBUL CHAUDHARY
No .
Is Mahendra still asleep ?
Yes .
How is Milady doing ?
It 's silly of me to ask .
Of course she must be devastated .
She must be in mourning ...
Satya Bulbbul
Do you have to leave ?
There 's nothing here for me .
Don 't worry .
I 'll keep sending money .
She hasn 't yet gained consciousness .
I have done the needful , but her feet ...
She fell from the stairs .
She fell from the stairs ?
Pay the doctor ,
and give him a little tip for his services .
I 'm sorry to bother you this early ,
but there has been another murder .
There 's a witness , a little girl . She seems to be in shock .
Poor thing . She was saying ...
What ?
The goddess killed him .
I would like to speak to her .
She 's sedated .
The doctor gave her a pill .
Which doctor ?
Dr. Sudip .
Fortunately , he was close at hand .
Thief .
It 's a fine .
You haven 't come to see me for days .
I thought Sir Satya is here , so you would be busy .
Oh , he 's the busy one .
He has a new hobby these days .
What were those stories you used to read to me ?
- The one with the detective . - Yes . Sherlock .
Yes .
So Satya is playing Sherlock these days .
It 's not a joke .
He suspects you .
Actually , there is not even a speck of truth to it . So why worry ?
Depends on what he suspects me of .
I have no expectations .
You know what ?
You are way out of my league .
Which is why I draw boundaries
to keep myself a little safe .
Coward .
Oh , yeah .
- Are these all the crime reports ? - Yes , Sir Satya .
This signature ?
It 's Dr. Sudip 's .
He came to examine the body .
What are these papers ?
It 's a story .
A scary story .
Want to hear it ?
A man comes to town ,
and suddenly , people start getting killed .
But this is not the scary bit .
A girl falls in his trap .
She forgets herself , and she forgets right from wrong .
She abandons all shame , all that was good and true about her
even her husband .
And then the unthinkable happens .
Her husband leaves her .
A nice story indeed .
Sister-in-law
enough .
You made a mistake .
We 'll assume ... you were alone ,
foolish ,
and Sudip took advantage of it .
Just come right out and say it . You 're jealous of Sudip .
Sister-in-law , stop saying his name .
Sudip .
Sister-in-law ...
How you have changed !
I have written to your husband
to ask for his advice .
I don 't think he will take you back ,
but maybe ... it would be best to send you back to your family .
You are all the same .
Milord ...
Doll .
Get up .
Get up !
Play , play .
Play !
No !
Play .
Play !
Get up .
Get up ! Get up !
Get up ! Get up ! Get up !
You have married into a royal family .
Why the tears ?
Keep quiet .
He 's a little
insane ,
but he 'll be fine after marriage .
He 's a little insane ,
but
he 's of royal blood .
Keep quiet .
He 's a little insane ,
but you will be adorned in jewels .
He 's a little insane , but
you will be draped in silks .
You will get respect .
Keep quiet .
He 's a little insane , but
if not him , then his brother
will look after you .
Large manors have large secrets .
So keep quiet .
- How is she ? - She 's regained consciousness .
I have told everyone that they shouldn 't touch your feet .
Careful .
You 've lost so much blood .
Who did this ?
I 'm your doctor . You can trust me .
Then do your job and leave .
Milady .
Everything is ready for the prayer meet .
Prayer meet ?
Prayers for Mahendra 's death anniversary .
How can I forget ?
It 's such a special day for us both .
Are you going somewhere ?
Don 't worry .
I won 't do anything .
The first time I met you ,
I wanted to put a bullet through you right then .
Now I know why .
Your fate will be decided by the courts in Calcutta .
Last night my father threw out my mother from the house last night .
His new wife made him do that ,
and now look what my mother has done .
Where is your father ?
He has taken Sir Satya .
Where ?
Aren 't you afraid ?
Of what ?
The consequences of your crimes .
You think you will get away with it .
If it depends on the law , then yes .
- I suspect you ... - You suspect something entirely different ,
but intend to punish me for another crime .
Although , there is a way .
I will believe you are completely innocent
if that Demon-Woman appears before us .
Driver ?
Driver !
Don 't move , or I 'll shoot .
Driver .
Have you fallen asleep ?
Straighten your feet .
How will you heal if you don 't ?
I have healed .
Milady .
- Milady ? - Doctor !
She was ... She was here !
There is a witch .
We have to find her .
- Let 's go . - Go back home , Sire .
What ?
Go back to your manor .
Why ?
I 'm not afraid of her .
If you are , you 're welcome to leave .
At least we know
you 're innocent .
You can leave .
- What are you doing ? - I 'm going to hunt her .
Sire , stop !
Why are you trying to stop me ?
Why are you trying to save her ? Who is she to you ?
She is just my friend ,
but isn 't she everything to you , your ...
Why such fondness for a demon ?
She 's not a demon .
She 's a goddess .
There 's a witness , a little girl .
She was saying ... the goddess killed him .
- Master Dinkar . - A fine man .
His wife 's broken bones tell another story .
The goddess has not done right by me .
I was immersed in prayers when the Demon-Woman killed Mahendra .
Milady !
What have you done ?
Why are you trying to save her ?
What is she to you ?
She is just my friend ,
but isn 't she everything to you , your sister-in-law ?
And it wasn 't an animal .
- It 's the work of a man . - Why ? Why not a woman ?
One , two ...
Three , four ...
Five , six ...
Seven , eight ...
Nine , ten ...
Eleven , 12 ...
Thirteen , 14 ...
Dear brother .
I always thought that when I grew up , I would like to be like you .
But I 'm leaving this house forever
because I 'm afraid .
I might become like you .
Because I 'm afraid ... I might already be like you .
Now we are literally related by blood :
The blood that has stained all our hands .
Now we are all the same .
Milord .
Bulbbul ?
Subtitle translation by Anju Choudhary